When we discuss food and which kinds of food we like we often need to use the word cuisine.
当我们讨论食物以及我们喜欢哪种食物时，我们经常需要使用美食这个词。
What exactly does it mean.
究竟是什么意思。
Kind of easy to misunderstand.
有点容易误会。
Well cuisine generally is a type of food that is specific to or connected to a particular place or culture.
美食通常是一种特定于特定地方或文化或与特定地方或文化相关的食物。
Now it could be a country but it doesn't have to be a country.
现在它可以是一个国家，但它不一定是一个国家。
For example you could have Japanese cuisine but then there might be a particular city that's famous
例如，您可能有日本料理，但可能有一个著名的特定城市
for food.
为了食物。
You might have for example New Orleans cuisine which is a famous type of cuisine in America or you could
例如，您可能有美国著名的新奥尔良美食，或者您可以
have for example a province name like in China.
例如，有一个像中国一样的省名。
You have Sichuan cuisine.
你有川菜。
So that's a particular area in China.
这是中国的一个特殊领域。
Then for each area in China you have different cuisines.
那么对于中国的每个地区，您都有不同的美食。
So usually it's related to a place but not necessarily it could be just cultural.
所以通常它与一个地方有关，但不一定是文化。
Any way we can say it's a type of food a cuisine is a type of food.
无论如何，我们可以说它是一种食物，美食就是一种食物。
So often when you hear people say what cuisines Do you like or what is your favorite cuisine you can
所以经常当你听到人们说你喜欢什么菜系或者你最喜欢什么菜系时你可以
just say the type of food you like Oh I like French cuisine I like Japanese cuisine I like Indian cuisine
就说你喜欢的食物类型哦我喜欢法国菜我喜欢日本菜我喜欢印度菜
I like Italian cuisine whatever you want to say.
无论你想说什么，我都喜欢意大利菜。
Now sometimes those things are not clear.
现在有时这些事情并不清楚。
For example if you say I like American cuisine you might have to describe what exactly you mean by that
例如，如果您说我喜欢美国菜，您可能需要准确描述您的意思
because that's less clearly defined than perhaps other countries such as French cuisine and Italian
因为这可能不像法国菜和意大利菜等其他国家那么明确
cuisine or Indian cuisine.
菜或印度菜。
We often use subjective adjectives and we're talking about the feeling we have about particular cuisines
我们经常使用主观形容词，我们谈论的是我们对特定美食的感觉
or the feeling that we have about maybe the taste of a particular food and it could be the overall feeling
或者我们对某种特定食物的味道的感觉，也可能是整体感觉
or it could be something more specific about the taste.
或者它可能是关于味道的更具体的东西。
Let me explain what I mean.
让我解释一下我的意思。
So take Indian food.
所以吃印度菜。
I like Indian food.
我喜欢印度菜。
How would you describe Indian food.
你会如何描述印度菜。
Well again it's quite it's quite subjective in some way.
好吧，这在某种程度上是相当主观的。
I would describe Indian food as a bit heavy and that's because after I eat Indian food I feel a bit
我会形容印度菜有点重，那是因为我吃了印度菜后感觉有点
a bit heavy.
有点重。
So I feel Indian food is a bit heavy.
所以我觉得印度菜有点重。
That's kind of subjective.
这有点主观。
But generally speaking it's more spicy than other cuisines.
但总的来说它比其他菜系更辣。
Many other cuisines so it's it's also spicy and that's more related to the particular taste of the food.
许多其他美食，所以它也很辣，这与食物的特殊味道更相关。
It's got a lot of different spices in it and it's very hot when you eat it.
它里面有很多不同的香料，吃的时候很热。
Some of it is OK.
其中一些是可以的。
So it's a bit heavy.
所以有点重。
That's my feeling and it's spicy.
这是我的感觉，而且很辣。
How about German food.
德国菜怎么样。
Well German food generally people describe as heavy again.
好吧，德国食物通常人们再次形容为重。
That's because the feeling of the food people eat it generally they feel it's quite heavy compared to
那是因为人们吃它的食物的感觉一般他们觉得它与
other types of food like for example Japanese food which people often describe as very light so heavy
其他类型的食物，例如日本食物，人们经常形容它们很轻很重
and light aren't exactly tastes.
和光不完全是口味。
Their overall feelings.
他们的整体感受。
What about the taste of Japanese food.
日本料理的味道怎么样。
Well it doesn't have a very strong taste typically.
嗯，它通常没有很强烈的味道。
For example like Indian food which might be very spicy which uses a lot of spices Japanese food is often
例如，像印度菜，它可能很辣，使用了很多香料，日本菜经常是
very simple and you could say it's very simple.
非常简单，你可以说它非常简单。
You could also say it's very mild.
你也可以说它非常温和。
M I L D mild.
M I L D 轻度。
If something doesn't have a particularly strong taste it's often described as mild mild is a word that
如果某物没有特别强烈的味道，它通常被描述为温和 温和是一个词
can also be used to describe whether you live in a place that doesn't have extremely hot weather in
也可以用来形容你是否住在一个没有极端炎热天气的地方
the summer and not extremely cold weather in the winter.
夏天而不是非常冬天天气寒冷。
Then maybe you live in a mild climate so a mild climate is sort of not too strong not that weak kind
那么也许你生活在温和的气候中，所以温和的气候不是太强，不是那么弱
of in the middle.
的在中间。
Gentle a bit gentle and you could go on with other adjectives that you feel are related to particular
温和一点，您可以继续使用您认为与特定相关的其他形容词
cuisines Sichuan food from China is famous for being very spicy and very oily it's very oily and very
中国的川菜以非常辣和非常油腻着称，非常油腻非常
spicy.
辛辣的。
You could say German food as I mentioned is very heavy but you might also say that it can be a bit bland.
你可以说我提到的德国菜很重，但你也可以说它可能有点乏味。
That means no offense to German food can be a little bit boring it's not very exciting like for example
这意味着对德国食物没有冒犯可能会有点无聊，这不是很令人兴奋，例如
like for example Indian food or maybe Thai food it's kind of an exciting cuisine.
例如印度菜或泰国菜，这是一种令人兴奋的美食。
Both of those are a bit exciting.
这两个有点令人兴奋。
They are they can be very spicy or Mexican food Mexican cuisine.
他们可以是非常辣的或墨西哥菜墨西哥菜。
So a lot of these are words that you choose based on your feeling but there are general words common
所以很多这些是你根据自己的感觉选择的词，但也有一些通用词
words that are associated associated to each type of food.
与每种食物相关联的词。
For example German food being heavy and Sichuan food being for example spicy and oily.
例如德国菜很重，四川菜又辣又油。
OK so when you're talking about cuisine use subjective adjectives and focus on the type of food whatever
好的，所以当您谈论美食时，请使用主观形容词并关注食物的类型
you want to say about it.
你想说一下。